Register of the Albert C. Wedemeyer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Albert C. Wedemeyer papers
1897-1988
83007
Hoover Institution Archives
148 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 14 oversize boxes, 2 motion picture film reels, 19 sound discs, 1 sound cassette, 2 maps, memorabilia (87.1 linear feet)
Orders, plans, memoranda, reports, correspondence, speeches and writings, clippings, printed matter, photographs, and memorabilia relating to Allied strategic planning during World War II, military operations in China, American foreign policy in China, and post-war American politics and foreign relations.
Wedemeyer, Albert C. (Albert Coady), 1896-1989.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Use copies of some sound recordings in the collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1983, with increments received in later years.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1896 July 9 Born, Omaha, Nebraska
1918 Commissioned Second Lieutenant, U. S. Army
1919 Graduated from United States Military Academy, West Point, New York
1919-1922 Assigned to Infantry School and 29th Infantry, Fort Benning, Georgia
1920 Promoted to First Lieutenant
1922-1923 Aide-de-Camp to Brigadier General Paul B. Malone at Fort Benning, Georgia, Fort Sill, Oklahoma, and Fort Sam Houston, Texas
1923-1925 Served with the 31st Infantry and 57th Infantry, Philippine Islands
1925-1930 Assigned to 12th Infantry, Fort Washington, Maryland
1927-1930 Aide-de-Camp to Commanding General, District of Washington
1930-1931 Served with 15th Infantry, Tientsin, China
1932-1934 Aide-de-Camp to Major General C. E. Kilbourne, Corregidor, Philippine Islands
1934 Attended the Command and General Staff School, Fort Leavenworth, Kansas
1935 Promoted to Captain
1936-1938 Student officer, German War College, Berlin, Germany
1938-1940 Assigned to 29th Infantry, Fort Benning, Georgia
1940 Promoted to Major
1940-1941 Assigned to Training Section, Office of the Chief of Infantry
1941-1942 Promoted to Lieutenant Colonel (temporary) Staff member, War Plans Division, War Department General
1942-1943 Promoted to Colonel (temporary), Brigadier General (temporary), and Lieutenant Colonel (permanent) Chief, Strategy and Policy Section, Operations Division, War Department
1943 Promoted to Major General (temporary)
1943-1944 Deputy Chief of Staff to Admiral Mountbatten, Combined Anglo-American South East Asia Command
1944-1946 Commanding General, United States Forces, China Theatre Chief of Staff to Chiang Kai-shek
1945 Promoted to Lieutenant General (temporary)
1946 Promoted to Brigadier General (permanent)
1946-1947 Commanding General, Second Army, Baltimore, Maryland
1947 Special Envoy to China and Korea
1947-1948 Director, Plans and Operations Division, General Staff, United States Army
1948-1949 Deputy Chief of Staff for Plans and Combat Operations
1949-1951 Commanding General, Sixth Army, San Francisco, California
1951 Retired with rank of Lieutenant General
1951-1956 Executive Vice President, AVCO Manufacturing Corporation
1952 Chairman, National Citizens for Taft
1954 Promoted to General on retired list
1956-1959 Executive Vice President, Rheem Manufacturing Company
1958 Author, Wedemeyer Reports!
1987 Author, Wedemeyer on War and Peace (edited by Keith Eiler)
1989 December 17 Died, Fort Belvoir, Virginia
Scope and Content of Collection
Orders, plans, memoranda, reports, correspondence, speeches and writings, clippings, printed matter, photographs, and memorabilia relating to Allied strategic planning during World War II, military operations in China, American foreign policy in China, and post-war American politics and foreign relations.
United States. Army--Officers.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; China--History--Civil War, 1945-1949.; United States--Foreign relations--China.; United States--Foreign relations--1945-1989.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--East Asia.; United States. War Department. General Staff.; Audiotapes.; Sound recordings.; Motion pictures.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1926-1988 (Boxes 1-5)
  Scope and Contents note
  Notes, memoranda, biographical sketches, itineraries, clippings, correspondence, legal documents, certificates, printed material, poems, resolutions, lists, speeches, newsletters, pamphlets, programs, and miscellany, arranged alphabetically by form.
  - General, 1926-1988 (Box-folder 1: 1)
    Lists, form letters, biographical outline, newsletter, memorandum, notes, quotations, poems, and printed material.
  - Appointment books, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Awards and honorary degrees
    - General, 1946-1987 (Box-folder 1: 3)
      Printed material, correspondence, and certificates.
    - Medal of Freedom, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 1: 4)
      Correspondence, printed material, and miscellany.
    - Nebraska Society, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 5)
      Speech by Carl Curtis, and correspondence with Curtis, E. Robert Anderson, Harry F. Byrd, Cortez F. Enloe, Roman Hruska, Melvin Laird, Richard Nixon, Richard Russell, Lowell Thomas and others.
  - Clippings
    - Undated (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - 1936-1959 (Box-folder 1: 7-8)
    - 1960-1988 (Box-folder 2: 1-2)
  - Congressional campaign material, 1960 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    Clippings and correspondence with R. Chesley McCormick, Roland W. McNamee, Ray Maddocks and others.
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1965-1985 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - Birthday letters, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 2: 5-10)
  - Decorations, 1943-1949 (Box-folder 2: 11)
    Letters and citations. See also: OVERSIZE FILE/Box 151.
  - Family and genealogical material, 1952-1983 (Box-folder 2: 12)
    Clipping, notes, correspondence, and printed material.
  - Passports, visas, and other identification papers, 1929-1981 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - References to Wedemeyer, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 3: 2-4)
    Printed excerpts.
  - Service records, 1936-1982 (Box-folder 3: 5)
    Memoranda, orders, and forms.
  - Trips
    Clippings, correspondence, itineraries, printed material, address and guest lists, and miscellany.
    - Undated (Box-folder 3: 6)
    - 1960 - 1965 October (Box-folder 3: 7-10)
    - 1965 December - 1973 (Box-folder 4: 1-10)
    - 1974-1981 (Box-folder 5: 1-4)
  - Wedding anniversary, 60th, 1985 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    Testimonials, program, and miscellany.
  - Wills, 1988 (Box-folder 5: 6)
    Letter and synopsis.
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1938-1988 (Boxes 5-23)
  Typescript and printed copies, serial issues, notes, interview transcripts, press releases, schedules, memoranda, correspondence, and clippings, arranged chronologically.
  - General
    - Correspondence, 1951-1988 (Box-folder 5: 7)
    - Fragments, holographs and typescripts, undated (Box-folder 5: 8)
    - Miscellany, speaking schedules, 1946-1976 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - "A Time for Action," printed copy, undated (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - "The China Theater Today," typescript, undated (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - "Chinese Culture and Communism," typescript, undated (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - "Commanders and Others Contacted,", undated (Box-folder 5: 13)
    Typescript descriptions of Dwight Eisenhower, George Patton, Truman Smith, and others.
  - "Communist Fifth Column Penetration in China," typescript, undated (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - "Dependence for Strategic Materials Has Led Us to Global Commitments," typescript and background report, undated (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - "Discipline and Morale," typescript, undated (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - "A Few Personal Observations on Eisenhower," typescript, undated (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - "Honor," typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - "How the Army Plans," Army Information Digest, typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Interview, transcript, undated (Box-folder 6: 3)
    Relates to World War II and China.
  - "Losing Our Victory," typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - "Mission to China in 1947," typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - "My First Months in China," typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - "Our National Defense Problem," typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - "Our Relations with China," typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - "Recognition of Red China," typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - "The Road Toward Permanent Peace," typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Speech on China, typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Speech on East Asia, typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - Speech on military planning, typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Statement on Chiang Kai-shek, typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - "Strategic Importance of the Far East," lecture, National War College, typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - "Subjects and Points to be Used in Talking to Officers of the Civilian Components or Civilians," typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - Untitled fragment on the Casablanca Conference, typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - Untitled fragment on Harry Hopkins, typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - Untitled fragment on Franklin D. Roosevelt, typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - Untitled fragments on Lucius Clay, typescripts, undated (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - Untitled fragments on communism, holographs and typescripts, undated (Box-folder 6: 21)
  - Untitled fragments on military planning, typescripts, undated (Box-folder 6: 22)
  - Untitled fragments on Vietnam, typescripts, undated (Box-folder 6: 23)
  - Untitled reply to E. J. Kahn, The China Hands, typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 24)
  - Untitled writing on Truman Smith, typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 25)
  - Untitled writing on Henry Stimson, typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 26)
  - Untitled writings on Chiang Kai-shek, typescripts, undated (Box-folder 6: 27)
  - Untitled writings on Winston Churchill, typescripts, undated (Box-folder 6: 28)
  - Untitled writings on foreign policy, typescripts, undated (Box-folder 6: 29)
  - Untitled writings on George Marshall, typescripts, undated (Box-folder 6: 30)
  - Untitled writings, fragments, and notes on China, typescripts, undated (Box-folder 6: 31)
  - Untitled writings, fragments, and notes on World War II, holographs and typescripts, undated (Box-folder 6: 32)
  - "Women's Role in National Security," typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 33)
  - "World War II Strategy and Its Significance Today," typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 34)
  - "Captain Wedemeyer's Report on the Kriegsakademie,", 1938 July 11 (Box-folder 6: 35)
    Typescript, memorandum, and correspondence, 1938-1985.
  - "Speech Before the Veterans of Foreign Wars," typescript, 1939 February 23 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - "A Historical, Strategic Study," typescript, 1940 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "Baron Wessel Frietag [sic?] von Loringhoven," typescript, 1944 March 4 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Speech, first official statement by Wedemeyer in China, typescript, 1944 November 4 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Speech, relates to China, typescript, 1945 January 28 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "Memorial Service for President Roosevelt, Chungking, China," typescript, 1945 April (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Radio broadcast, statement on the end of the war in Europe, typescript, 1945 May 8 (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - "General Wedemeyer Issues Fourth of July Message," typescript and printed copy, 1945 July 4 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - "Franklin D. Roosevelt,", 1945 July (Box-folder 7: 9)
    Typescript and letter, 1945.
  - Radio broadcast, statement on the end of the war in Asia, typescript, 1945 August 13 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Statement, CBI Edition Newsmap, printed copy, 1945 September 17 (Box-folder 7: 11)
    See also: POSTER COLLECTION/U.S. 8778
  - "A Strong and Independent China," typescript, circa 1945-1946 (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - "To the Officers and Enlisted Men of China Theater," typescript, circa 1945-1946 (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - "Activities in the China Theater," typescript, circa 1946 (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - Statement, radio station dedication, Nanking, China, typescript, 1946 March-April (Box-folder 7: 15)
  - Statement, farewell speech upon departure from China, typescript, 1946 April 2 (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - Speech, Conference of Army Chaplains, Baltimore, typescript, 1946 June 17-18 (Box-folder 7: 17)
  - Speech, dedication ceremonies, Beatrice, Nebraska, typescript, 1946 September 8 (Box-folder 7: 18)
  - Speech, World War II veterans celebration, Berryville, Virginia, typescript, 1946 October 19 (Box-folder 7: 19)
  - Speech, Women's Club, Baltimore, typescript, 1946 October 25 (Box-folder 7: 20)
  - Speech, Advertising Club, Baltimore, typescript, 1946 October 30 (Box-folder 7: 21)
  - Speech, Armistice Day, Charleston, West Virginia, typescript, 1946 November 11 (Box-folder 7: 22)
  - "Current Situation in China," speech, National War College, Washington, D.C., typescript and typescript discussion outline, 1946 November 18 (Box-folder 7: 23)
  - Speech, Kiwanis Club, typescript, 1946 November 21 (Box-folder 7: 24)
  - Radio broadcast, Baltimore, Maryland, typescript, 1946 December 6 (Box-folder 7: 25)
  - Speech, Kiwanis Club, Philadelphia, typescript, 1946 December 9 (Box-folder 7: 26)
  - Speech, China Institute in America, New York, New York, 1947 January 27 (Box-folder 7: 27)
    Typescript and notes, 1947.
  - "Observations on Europe,", 1947 May (Box-folder 7: 28)
    Typescript report and miscellany, 1947.
  - "Projected American Strategy," Kermit Roosevelt Memorial lectures, Imperial Defense College and Camberly Staff College, Great Britain, 1947 May 21-28 (Box-folder 7: 29)
    Memoranda, printed material, and letters by Alfred M. Gruenther, Charles Keightley, Bella (Mrs. Kermit) Roosevelt and Maxwell Taylor, 1947-1986.
  - "The Education of the United States Army Officer," Kermit Roosevelt memorial lecture, Sandhurst, Great Britain, mimeograph, 1947 May 29 (Box-folder 7: 30)
  - Radio broadcast, Army Air Force Day, China, typescript, 1947 August (Box-folder 7: 31)
  - Press conference, Shanghai, China, transcript, 1947 August 14 (Box-folder 7: 32)
  - The Wedemeyer Report - China and Korea (pamphlet), printed copy, 1947 September (Box-folder 7: 33)
  - "Strategy," speech, Armed Forces Staff College, Norfolk, Virginia, typescript and mimeograph, 1947 November 10 (Box-folder 7: 34)
  - "China," lecture, National War College, Washington, D.C., typescript, 1947 November 24 (Box-folder 7: 35)
  - Statement, Senate Appropriations Committee, 1947 December 17 (Box-folder 7: 36)
    Relates to U.S. aid to China. Typescript and clippings, 1947-1948.
  - "Communism vs. Chiang in China," typescript, 1948? (Box-folder 7: 37)
  - "Army War Time Requirements," statement, Senate (?) Armed Services Committee, typescript, 1948 January 12 (Box-folder 7: 38)
  - Speech, Foreign Policy Association, Cincinnati, Ohio, typescript, 1948 January 15 (Box-folder 7: 39)
  - "U.S. Post War Strategy," lecture, National War College, Washington, D.C., discussion transcript, typescript, 1948 January 27 (Box-folder 7: 40)
  - Speech, Ohio Newspaper Association, Columbus, Ohio, typescript, 1948 February 5 (Box-folder 7: 41)
  - Speech, Air War College, Maxwell Field, Alabama, typescript, 1948 March 2 (Box-folder 7: 42)
  - "Army War Time Requirements," statement, House Foreign Affairs Committee, 1948 March 4 (Box-folder 7: 43)
    Relates to U.S. aid to China. Typescript and correspondence, 1948.
  - Speech, American Legion, Omaha, Nebraska, typescript, 1948 March 9 (Box-folder 7: 44)
  - Speech, Friendly Sons of Saint Patrick, Philadelphia, typescript, 1948 March 17 (Box-folder 7: 45)
  - "World Situation and Tasks of the Army Department," typescript, 1948 March 29 (Box-folder 7: 46)
  - Speech, Military Order of World Wars, Los Angeles, mimeograph, 1948 April 6 (Box-folder 7: 47)
  - "Presentation to the American Legion," typescripts, 1948 April 27 (Box-folder 7: 48)
  - "Global Strategy," speech, State Department, Washington, D.C., typescripts, 1948 May 6 (Box-folder 7: 49)
  - Commencement address, Lebanon Valley College, Annville, Pennsylvania, mimeograph, 1948 May 31 (Box-folder 7: 50)
  - Statement, Senate Appropriations Committee, typescript, 1948 June 10 (Box-folder 7: 51)
    Relates to U.S. military aid to China.
  - Television interview, Baltimore Museum of Art, Baltimore, typescript, 1948 August 15 (Box-folder 7: 52)
  - Speech, Department of the Army, Pentagon, Alexandria, Virginia, typescript, 1948 September 21 (Box-folder 7: 53)
  - Speech, Women's Advisory Council, Pentagon, Alexandria, Virginia, typescript and agenda, 1948 September 22 (Box-folder 7: 54)
  - Interview, We the People, television broadcast, Washington, D.C., typescript, 1948 October 12 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - "Talk to Section V Committee, National Guard and Reserve," typescript, 1948 November 9 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - "Strategy," Armed Forces Staff College, Norfolk, Virginia, 1948 November 22 (Box-folder 8: 3)
    Typescript, and typescript copy of a speech by J. L. Collins, "The Role of the Army in Future Warfare," 1948.
  - "Strategy for Peace," typescript, 1949 January 31 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - "U.S. Postwar Strategy," lecture, National War College, Washington, D.C., 1949 February 17 (Box-folder 8: 5)
    Typescript discussion transcript, letter, and course material, 1949.
  - Statement, Joint Committee on Foreign Economic Cooperation, U.S. Congress, typescript, 1949 March 14 (Box-folder 8: 6)
    Relates to Chinese communists.
  - Speech, Union League Club, Philadelphia, typescript, 1949 April 6 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - "Strategy," Air University, Maxwell Field, Alabama, 1949 April 14 (Box-folder 8: 8)
    Typescript and correspondence, 1949.
  - "A Strategic Plan for Peace," Investment Bankers Association, White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia, typescript and printed copy, 1949 May 20 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - Speech, new officer orientation, Department of the Army, Pentagon, Washington, D.C., typescript, 1949 May 24 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Commencement address, Infantry School, Fort Benning, Georgia, typescript, 1949 June 24 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - "China-Burma-India History," typescript memorandum, 1949 July 6 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - Statement, House Appropriations Committee, typescript, 1949 August 7 (Box-folder 8: 13)
    Relates to the attitude of the Army toward the Voice of America program.
  - Speeches, National Security Industrial Association and Chamber of Commerce, San Francisco, 1949 November 14-16 (Box-folder 8: 14)
  - "The Strength to Lead," National Convention of the Grange, Sacramento, typescript, 1949 November 22 (Box-folder 8: 15)
  - Speech, Presidio Officers' Club, San Francisco, typescript, 1949 December 9 (Box-folder 8: 16)
  - Statement, contribution to a film project by Standard of California, typescript, 1949 December 21 (Box-folder 8: 17)
  - "Our Modern Military Role," typescript, 1950 (Box-folder 8: 18)
  - "Remarks by General Wedemeyer Before the Japanese Diet," welcoming speech, San Francisco, California, typescript, 1950 January 16 (Box-folder 8: 19)
  - Speech, Junior League Club and Presidio Officers' Club, San Francisco, typescript, 1950 January 17 and 19 (Box-folder 8: 20)
  - "The Formulation of Grand Strategy," National War College, Washington, D.C., typescripts and outline, 1950 February 10 (Box-folder 8: 21)
  - Speech, American Nurses Association, San Francisco, mimeograph, 1950 May 8 (Box-folder 8: 22)
  - Speech, Rotary Club, Sacramento, mimeograph, 1950 May 18 (Box-folder 8: 23)
  - Welcoming statement, Armed Forces Day, Presidio of San Francisco, mimeograph, 1950 May 20 (Box-folder 8: 24)
  - Commencement address, Creighton University, Omaha, Nebraska, typescript and mimeograph, 1950 June 1 (Box-folder 8: 25)
  - Remarks on the retirements of Frank L. Cole and Walter M. Robertson, typescripts, 1950 June 28 and 30 (Box-folder 8: 26)
  - "Grand Strategy," speech, National War College, Washington, D.C., 1950 August 30 (Box-folder 8: 27)
    Typescripts, mimeograph, and letter, 1950.
  - Statement, commemoration of the Chinese Double Tenth anniversary, 1950 September 28 (Box-folder 8: 28)
    Typescript and correspondence, 1950.
  - Brief statements, community events, San Francisco, typescripts, 1950 October (Box-folder 8: 29)
  - "Remarks at Closing Session Field Economic Mobilization Course," Salt Lake City, Utah, typescripts, 1950 October 6 (Box-folder 8: 30)
  - "Strategy," speech, Army Advisory Committee, San Francisco, California, mimeograph, 1950 October 18 (Box-folder 8: 31)
  - Press release requesting blood donors for Korea, typescript, 1950 November (Box-folder 8: 32)
  - Radio broadcast, typescript, 1950 November 2 (Box-folder 8: 33)
    Relates to blood donations.
  - "General Wedemeyer's Radio Address on Civil Defense," Portland, Oregon, typescript, 1950 November 3 (Box-folder 8: 34)
  - Speech, Chamber of Commerce, San Francisco, mimeograph, 1950 November 16 (Box-folder 8: 35)
  - Speech, Chamber of Commerce, Oakland, California, mimeograph, 1950 December 15 (Box-folder 8: 36)
  - Statement, Associated Services Armed Forces broadcast, memorandum and typescripts, 1950 December 18 (Box-folder 8: 37)
  - Statement, Christmas greetings to the 6th Army, mimeograph, 1950 December 18 (Box-folder 8: 38)
  - "Ideas for Pamphlet on Strategy," typescript, 1950 December 31 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - "This I Believe," radio broadcast, typescript, 1951 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - "Statement by General Wedemeyer for Crusade for Freedom," typescript and letter to Harold Stassen, 1951 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - Questionnaire, Look, 1951 January 28 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    Relates to propaganda. Typescript and letter, 1951.
  - "Address Delivered Before Joint Meeting of Idaho State Legislature," speech, Boise, Idaho, mimeograph, 1951 February 7 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Letter to the editor, Daily Idahonian, printed copy (incomplete), 1951 February 15 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - Speech, Community Chest, San Francisco, mimeograph, 1951 March 5 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - "Remarks Before Oregon State Legislature," speech, Salem, Oregon, typescript, 1951 March 9 (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - "Remarks Before Red Cross Program," speech, San Francisco, California, typescript, 1951 March 18 (Box-folder 9: 9)
  - Speech, Children's Hospital, San Francisco, typescript, 1951 April 19 (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - Testimony, U.S. Congress, 1951 May (Box-folder 9: 11)
    Relates to the Wedemeyer report on China. Clippings, and typescript drafts of questionnaires and Wedemeyer statement, 1951.
  - "The American Citizen--Defender of Freedom," speech, Armed Forces Day, Lincoln, Nebraska, 1951 May 15 (Box-folder 9: 12)
    Mimeograph and memorandum, 1951.
  - Speeches, Memorial Day, San Francisco Bay area, typescripts, 1951 May 30 (Box-folder 9: 13)
  - Commencement address, University of San Francisco, San Francisco, typescript and mimeograph, 1951 June 3 (Box-folder 9: 14)
  - Testimony, Joint Armed Services-Foreign Relations Committee, 1951 June 11-12 (Box-folder 9: 15)
    Relates to China and Douglas MacArthur. Mimeograph, clippings, and correspondence, 1951.
  - Commencement address, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, mimeograph, 1951 June 16 (Box-folder 9: 16)